<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Evolve Data Science</title>
    <link>http://evolvedatascience.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Evolve Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://evolvedatascience.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ReallyIsTrump Tweet Predictor</title>
      <link>http://evolvedatascience.com/post/reallyistrump-tweet-predictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>http://evolvedatascience.com/post/reallyistrump-tweet-predictor/</guid>
      <description>Determining if tweets from @realDonaldTrump are written by the President or his staff Donald Trump’s proclivity for using Twitter has changed how the White House interacts with the media and broadcasts to the president’s followers. It’s also lead to a birth of a new academic subject and hobby for data analysts. People have studied how engagement has changed during his first 100 days and conducted sentiment analysis of his tweets both during the campaign and as president.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Nile Virus in Chicago, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://evolvedatascience.com/post/2016-12-17-wnv-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>http://evolvedatascience.com/post/2016-12-17-wnv-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>This project will explore and analyze a dataset for West Nile Virus (WNV) detection in mosquitoes that were captured using traps around Chicago, IL. The data sets originate from the Kaggle competition, West Nile Virus Prediction. Even though the competition for this data set is over, I like using data sets from Kaggle to practice data viz and machine learning for the following reasons.
The data is structured so there is instant gratification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grupo Bimbo Report</title>
      <link>http://evolvedatascience.com/post/grupo-bimbo-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>http://evolvedatascience.com/post/grupo-bimbo-report/</guid>
      <description>Grupo Bimbo Technical Report Project Overview Our client, Grupo Bimbo, wants to develop a model to accurately forecast inventory demand based on the historical sales data they collect. Grupo Bimbo is a large bakery store chain that has more than 2500 products spanning over one million stores. Their goal is to meet the product demand for their customers while minimizing unsold surplus. Our group is tasked to create a model to accurately forecast inventory demand based on the historical sales data provided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>