<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Evolve Data Science</title>
    <link>/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Evolve Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Keith Hultman</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Keith is a data loving nerd with a background in genetics who was seduced by business applications of statistical models and A/B testing. He has over 10 years of experience as a molecular geneticist with a focus on computational biology and statistical methods. He is currently transitioning into data science consulting.
Download my Resume (PDF)
Scientific experience  Extensive experience in generating original research ideas, following through with vigorous literature research, experimental design and execution Expert geneticist with extensive experience in Next-Generation Sequencing and gene expression analysis Wet-lab experience includes large-scale forward genetic mutant screens and pharmacogenetic interactions using small molecule drug discovery methods  Skills  Data Analytic Methods: Linear and logistic regression, supervised and unsupervised machine learning, A/B testing and hypothesis testing, and textual analysis Data Software: Proficient in R, Excel, and Perl for data analysis and model testing; proficient in creating data visualizations using Excel, ggplot, and Tableau; experience with Microsoft SQL Server for database and data warehousing Writing: Proficient in technical writing with track record of peer-reviewed publications, grant writing, and editing Presenting: Charismatic and confident public speaker with experience presenting to technical and lay audiences using Tableau and PowerPoint Other Software: Proficient in Word, Camtasia (screen recording), Photoshop, and Illustrator; general programming fluency in Perl, C, Java, and Python  He loves to rock climb whenever he gets the chance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>