<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Keith Hultman</title>
    <link>/blogdown2/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Keith Hultman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/blogdown2/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/blogdown2/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>/blogdown2/page/about/</guid>
      <description> Keith is a data loving nerd with a background in genetics who was seduced by business applications of statistical models and A/B testing.
He loves to rock climb whenever he gets the chance.
Educational Background  MS Data Science, Elmhurst University, 2017 PhD Molecular Genetics and Genomics, Washington University in St. Louis, 2009 BA Biology, University of St. Thomas, 2001  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up RStudio on AWS for a Bioinformatics class</title>
      <link>/blogdown2/page/2016-09-23-how-to-set-up-rstudio-on-aws-for-bioinformatics-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>/blogdown2/page/2016-09-23-how-to-set-up-rstudio-on-aws-for-bioinformatics-class/</guid>
      <description>Motivations for the RStudio course server This fall is probably the most enjoyable semester I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had teaching. I had an opportunity to design and run an upper-level special topics course on bioinformatics at Elmhurst College. It&amp;rsquo;s a class I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to teach because for me, it&amp;rsquo;s like being able to organize a class around everything I would have wanted to know before going to graduate school for genetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorite Data Exploration</title>
      <link>/blogdown2/page/2015-09-07-meteor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>/blogdown2/page/2015-09-07-meteor/</guid>
      <description>Meteor data exploration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Nile Virus in Chicago, Part 1</title>
      <link>/blogdown2/page/2016-12-17-wnv-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keithh@gmail.com (Keith Hultman)</author>
      <guid>/blogdown2/page/2016-12-17-wnv-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>This project will explore and analyze a dataset for West Nile Virus (WNV) detection in mosquitoes that were captured using traps around Chicago, IL. The data sets originate from the Kaggle competition, West Nile Virus Prediction. Even though the competition for this data set is over, I like using data sets from Kaggle to practice data viz and machine learning for the following reasons.
 The data is structured so there is instant gratification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>